Vivian Ngo

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An academic-oriented student with a 3.98/4.00 cumulative GPA, 3+ years of teaching and mentorship experience in mathematics, and industry work experience in analytics at two large corporations. Possesses a passion for mathematics and statistics and believes that it is essential to learn through practice and understanding as this leads to maturity in the subject area as well as an appreciation for the material. Currently exploring the field of statistics and its applications through applied statistics courses and research initiatives.

EDUCATION

Enrolled in Statistics Specialist and Mathematics Major Programs at University of Toronto

- 3.98/4.00 cGPA, 4.00/4.00 cGPA in all Mathematics and Statistics courses
- Obtained OSSD at William Lyon Mackenzie C.I
 - Graduated from enrichment MaCS Program (Mathematics and Computer Sciences)

RELATED SKILLS

- **Computer Skills:** Experience with Python, SQL, R, shell scripts, Microsoft software including Excel VBA, LaTex, as well as *Cisco IT Essentials Certification*.
- **Statistics:** Formal training in applied statistics and theoretical statistics. Currently participating in research statistics and learning additional statistical methods. 90%+ in all statistics courses.
- Data Analysis: Able to extract, clean, and transform data for purposes of analysis and reporting
- **Time Management:** Able to handle multiple responsibilities at once and deliver quality results.
- Language skills: Fluent in Cantonese, Vietnamese, and English.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Teaching Assistant at Statistical Sciences Department, University of Toronto (January 2019 April 2019)
- Research Assistant at Rotman School of Management, University of Toronto (September 2018 February 2019)
- Risk Analyst Intern, Technology and Operations Risk at BMO Financial Group (May 2018 August 2018)
 - o Used Python and Excel VBA to extract and transform data.
 - Analyzed financial data for VP of Technology and Operations Risk to assist with understanding of the Bank's expenditures
 - Created user-friendly applications for multiple BMO operating groups to help automate processes that are refreshed on a monthly, quarterly or annual basis
 - o Conducted research for VP of Technology and Operations Risk regarding managerial strategies to improve internal functionality and effectiveness of business implementations
- Business Analyst Co-op, Statistical Analytics at Precima, LoyaltyOne (May 2017 August 2017)
 - o Used SQL, Python, and shell scripts to extract, clean, and transform customer and item-level data for purposes of analysis, reporting, model scoring, and maintenance
 - o Interpreted, documented, and presented analytical results
 - o Used Python and Excel to extract item-level data, create statistical functions, and automate processes such as Cramer's V calculations and report production
- Math Instructor at Mathnasium the Math Learning Center (November 2015 April 2017)
 - o Taught students based on Grade 1 to 12 curriculum using the team teaching method
 - Provided mathematical instruction and assistance to help students catch up, keep up, and get ahead

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Statistical Sciences Mentorship Director (September 2017 August 2018)
- Statistical Sciences Union Member (September 2016 Present)
- University of Toronto Math Union Member (2016-2017)
- COMC Data Entry and Marking Party Volunteer (November 2016)
- Girls Count Too: Mathematics Program Mentor (2013 2015)
- *Food Club* Co-president (2014 2015)
 - Hosted biweekly meetings and prepared cooking supplies to share cooking techniques and recipes to encourage healthy eating.
- *Mackenzie Science Council* President (2014 2015)
 - o Arranged and hosted Science Olympics and competitions for 11 schools
 - o Represented school in several events at three University Science Olympics
- *Mackenzie Science Council* Event Designer (2013-2014)
 - Designed biweekly events for the science club
- Mackenzie Science Council Member (2011-2013)
- *Math Clinic* Tutor (2013 2015)
 - o Tutored math for students in grades 9 and 10
- Fundraiser for *Youth Assisting Youth* (2012 2015)

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Teacher's Assistant at Lamberton Public School
- Baycrest Hospital Youth Volunteer
- Epilepsy Toronto Fundraiser
- Neighborhood Math Tutor

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Later Life Learning Scholarship (2018)
 - o (CGPA is in the top 2 percentile of the undergraduate population)
- J.J. Stren Scholarship (2018)
- Samuel Beatty In-Course Scholarship (2017)
- Innis College Exceptional Achievement Award (2016)
- Later Life Learning OSOTF Award (2016)
- Dean's List Scholar (2016)
- Earned Certificate of Completion for Cisco IT Essentials (2015)
- Received U of T Scholars Award (2015)
 - o Awarded to first year students based on outstanding achievement.
- 3rd place in Innovamasters Engineering and Business Competition (2014)
- 2nd place in Fermi Competition at London Science Olympics (2014)
- Top 25% score in Canadian Senior Mathematics Contest (2014)
- Top 30% score in Fermat Mathematics Contest (2014)
- Honour Roll (2008-2015)